Priyanga Madhavan

Web Designer

+91-9092092897 • Dharmapuri, India priyamadhavan11@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/priya-madhavan/

Portfolio: https://priyanga.netlify.app/

Voluntary Designer at: https://laravelchennai.in/

A **Web Designer** with a broad set of skills with an In-depth understanding of Web technologies. Having a progressive 4+ years of experience in various front-end technologies, performing well in competitive environments. An enthusiastic achiever with a solid background of the coding standards and guidelines necessary for building successful and world-class web applications. Highly skilled in solving complex and logical business problems for clients. Committed to improving the quality of life on the individual and social level.

CORE COMPETENCIES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Web Development & Maintenance
- Front End Development
- Multi Platform Maintenance
- Responsive Designs

- Requirement Gathering
- Client Relationship Management

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• OS: Windows, Linux

 Backend: Laravel, BigCommerce, Magento, Wordpress

• Version Control: Git

- Frontend: HTML, CSS, LESS, SASS, JavaScript
- Frontend Frameworks: Bootstrap,
 - Tailwind CSS
- Tools: Photoshop, Figma
 Other Skills: Banner/Poster Designs, Wireframe Design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UI Developer

Oct 2021 — Present

Majulah Infotech Pvt Ltd (Subsidiary of Infotech Singapore)

As one of the leading companies that excels in cloud-based HR Software. Integrated Cloud HRMS Software Provider. Mobile Attendance App with Face Recognition & GPS location.

Environment: HTML5, CSS, Figma, Bootstrap3 and above.

Product Development & Maintenance

 Design the layout & web application for HRMS website revamp with multi language feature.

Front End Developer

June 2018 — August 2020

DCKAP Technologies, Tamil Nadu, India

One of the products of DCKAP is QA Touch which is a Test Case management tool for QA teams with over 3000+ clients.

Environment: Laravel, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Product Development & Maintenance

- Designed & Created dynamic component which reduced the overall development work & increased productivity by automating the iterative work.
- Coordinated with the team members to eradicate the redundant pages and refactored the code effectively
- Revamped the entire product's design which was out-dated templates to current industry standards level design.

One of the services of DCKAP end-to-end ecommerce solutions by developing online stores on top ecommerce platforms like Magento, Bigcommerce.

Environment in Bigcommerce: Stencil framework, HTML, CSS, SASS.

Platform: Magento and Bigcommerce

Website Development & Maintenance

• Customized the theme, developing and improving their client's ecommerce website using the magento framework and bigcommerce framework.

Web Designer

August 2017 — June 2018

Tranxit Technologies Solutions, Chennai, India

Tranxit is a Comprehensive Development Services such as Web app Development, Mobile app Development, IOS Development, Blockchain Development offering web & business solutions for clients.

Environment: Theme Customization, Wordpress , HTML , CSS , BOOTSTRAP, Photoshop.

Website Development & Maintenance

- Acquired multiple clients by Spearheading, R&D and development of Asset Management Components in the product.
- Designed & implemented the websites & time to mind to minimize the loading time.
- Played a major role to bring about standardized coding techniques and refactoring of major modules which improved the quality & speed of the websites.

Web Designer

June 2016 — August 2017

Yaksha Animations Studio, Chennai, India

Yaksha is focused on Augmented Reality, Virtual Reality & mixed Reality web development and 2D & 3D content creation.

Environment: Wordpress, HTML, CSS, BOOTSTRAP

Website Development & Maintenance

- Conceptualizing and Implementing creative ideas for client websites from the scratch.
- Maintaining the appearance of websites & preparing design plans and presenting the website structure.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor's of Electronics & Communication Engineering
Erode Sengunthar College of Engineering, Tamil Nadu, India

July 2011 — June 2015

REFERENCES

Dipthi Rajagopal,

Human Resources Department, DCKAP Technology +91-9952800578 dipthir@dckap.com Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India